aadl.org 2015-12-30

# Ann Arbor District Library Privacy Statement Policy | Ann Arbor District Library

This document details the assurances and intentions of the Ann Arbor District Library's (AADL) approach to privacy.

**Information Collection and Use**  
AADL is the sole user of the information collected on our website or at our facilities. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. AADL collects information from our users at several different points.

**Internet Use**  
In order to use the Internet stations at an AADL branch, a user must provide his/her name and address and show valid identification. This information is only used in the event that the user breaks one of the AADL rules of behavior during his/her session. The information collected is destroyed daily. No logs are kept as to what content is viewed during a session.

**Obtaining a Library Card**  
In order to obtain a library card, patrons must provide photo ID and proof of current address.

If patrons choose to provide an email address on their library card application, this information will only be used to deliver AADL notices. Email addresses will never be sold to or shared with others.

**Minor's Library Records**  
The person who becomes liable for payment for or return of the materials identified in the library record of a minor by signing the minor’s application for a library card shall designate to whom the minor’s library record may be released by filling out the Release of Minor Child’s Library Record section on the application.

**Checking out Materials**  
When an AADL cardholder checks out an item, that information is recorded for the purpose of determining due dates and overdue fines. Holds are also recorded as part of a cardholder's record. However, when the book is returned, or the reserved item is picked up and returned, this information is removed from the patron's record by default. Patrons may choose to have their checkout history recorded for their own use. This information can only be accessed by the cardholder via aadl.org. Patrons have the ability to delete any or all records from their history, or turn off the recording of checkouts at any time.

**Board Meetings**  
In order to make a citizen's comment at an AADL Board Meeting, a citizen will be asked to present his/her name and address. The information given will not be used in any other way.

**Donating to the Library**  
When a donation is given to AADL, we will record the donor's name, address and type and amount of gift to comply with AADL auditing procedures and to issue the donor a receipt for tax purposes. This information will never be given or sold to other organizations. Donor information will be used internally to further AADL development efforts.

**Comment Cards and Online Forms**  
When a patron fills out a comment card or online comment form, he/she can optionally provide his/her name, address, and email address. This enables AADL to respond to patrons’ comments. This information will not be shared or sold to other organizations.

**Log Files**  
When a user visits our website, his/her IP address is recorded. We use this information to analyze trends, administer the site, determine popularity of content, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

**Sharing**  
We may share aggregated information, such as traffic rates and browser types, with the public. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person.

**Links**  
The AADL web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that AADL is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by AADL.

**Newsletter**  
If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and email address.

**Surveys**  
From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code, age level). Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of AADL.

**Notification of Changes**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on our Homepage so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will send a notice to the email addresses given to us by our users. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. 

_Policy adopted by the Ann Arbor District Library Board June 11, 2001  
Revisions adopted November 21, 2005, June 19, 2006 and February 17, 2014_
